Alexandra R. Kauffman

Los Angeles, California <u>arkauffma@gmail.com</u> - <u>github.com/arkauffman</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/alexandrakauffman</u> - <u>alexandrakauffman.com</u>

Summary

"Those who imagine anything can create the impossible." Alan Turing and I share the same sentiment. I love creating something from nothing, and using my imagination to implement the complexities of a web development project. Prior to being a web developer, I was a student at the University of Wisconsin-Madison where I earned a degree in Communication Arts and a certificate in Computer Science. Within the many Computer Science courses I took there, I learned the art of pseudocoding, the value of debugging, and the theory behind Computer Science. I have worked with many programming languages, including HTML, CSS, React, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails and Java.

Skills

Javascript | Java | HTML | CSS | jQuery | Ruby | Ruby on Rails | React | Node.JS | Mongoose | MongoDB | Express | Git/GitHub | Bash | RESTful Programming | External APIs | Bootstrap | Materialize | WordPress

Projects

Munchin'

September 2017

• Munchin' allows a user to search through recipes provided by Yummly's API. A user can favorite or unfavorite a recipe in order to add or remove items from their grocery shopping list. This application was built with HTML, CSS, Materialize, React, JSX, Express, Node.JS, MongoDB and Yummly's API; this agile software was developed in a 4-day sprint.

Trendsy July 2017

• Trendsy allow a user to create or sign into their personal account, browse through items other users are selling, sort through items by category, upload/edit their own items and checkout with their current cart. This interface was built using HTML, CSS, Materialize, Ruby, Ruby on Rails and ERD; this agile software was developed in a 5-day sprint.

Potluckticality August 2017-Current

• Potluckticality allows a user to create or sign into their personal account, create events, invite friends to events and share with their friends what dishes they are bringing. It has been built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Materialize, Google OAuth, Nodemailer, Express and Node.JS.

List Me Up August 2017

• List Me Up text messages a user the items in their todo list as well as the weather for their current location at a specified time they provide. This application was built using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, EJS, AJAX requests, Node.JS, Express, Twilio API, Dark Sky API and Node Scheduler; this agile software was developed as a group in a 5-day sprint.

Experience

Freelance Full Stack Developer - Impeccable Looks | Los Angeles, CA September 2017-Current

• Working on making this photography website interactive and user-friendly. Made with HTML, CSS, React, Express, Node.JS and MongoDB.

Entrepreneur - Nails By Alex, Owner | Madison, WI

August 2014-May 2017

Built a "come to you" manicure business at the University of Wisconsin-Madison based on social
media and referrals. Managed a personal website in which clients made appointments. Performed
all public relations, revenue management, promotional writing, and social media platform
management.

Education

University of Wisconsin-Madison

• Bachelor of Arts, Communication Arts & Certificate, Computer Science General Assembly - Web Development Immersive Program May 2017 September 2017